# **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

Full stack developer – 17+ years of client, server, database, and API development deployed to cloud platforms

Technology enthusiast – active consumer and contributor to modern open-source projects

Proven leadership – experience leading small to medium teams in an agile software lifecycle

Military service – served 12 years honorably in the United States Air Force; Currently serving in the DE ANG

Active security clearance – TS/SCI, periodic reinvestigation completed June, 2017

Multi-Agency SBI and polygraph – CI polygraph completed September, 2017; FSP suitable

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE SUBJECT MATTER EXPERT

August 2015 to Present

Novetta, Fort Washington, MD & Arlington, VA

- Designed and developed next-gen Base Defense Operations platform for United States Air Force using Node, React, MobX-State-Tree, Chakra UI, PostgreSQL, Mapbox/MapLibre
- Developed enterprise application in support of Counterterrorism Division, Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) using Node, Babel, Webpack, Angular 2, SASS, MongoDB
- Developed big-data web application in support of Air Force Information System Security Office (ISSO) using Django, AngularJS, D3, PostgreSQL, ElasticSearch, Leaflet, and AWS; Lead migration to ReactJS and GraphQL
- Developed facial detection and recognition rapid prototype for internal R&D project using Node, Meteor, D3, MongoDB,
   Python, and OpenCV

## PRINCIPAL SOFTWARE ENGINEER

November 2013 to August 2015

Global Risk Advisors, Washington, DC, New York, NY & San Francisco, CA

- Developed secure web portal for executive clients allowing remote access to intelligence briefs and sensitive documents using PHP, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, and MySQL
- · Developed interactive info graphics using JavaScript, D3

#### LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

November 2011 to November 2013

International Business Machines, Pentagon, Washington, DC & ISAF HQ, Kabul, Afghanistan

- Designed and developed Intelligence, Surveillance, and Reconnaissance (ISR) data mart, aggregating data from multiple DoD sources in support of Office of the Undersecretary of Defense for Intelligence (OUSDI)
- Rapidly developed and deployed web applications to collect survey data from U.S. Forces Afghanistan and briefed analytic findings to senior United States decision makers
- · Developed and maintained custom Microsoft Office and Python tools for data ETL, KML parsing and generation

## SYSTEMS SOFTWARE ENGINEER

March 2004 to November 2011

United States Air Force, Tinker AFB, OK & White House Communications Agency, Washington, DC

- Developed the first web based mission planning and tracking system for Presidential Airlift Group (PAG) ensuring
  integrity of data and increased communication for all Presidential air travel missions using ASP .NET, C#, HTML,
  JavaScript, CSS, and MySQL
- Pioneered automated regression testing for the 552d Communications Squadron supporting the Airborne Warning And Control System (AWACS) platform

#### **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

USAF Computer Systems Programming Course USAF Cyber Warfare Operations Course

SANS SEC542: Web App Penetration Testing and Ethical Hacking Certification